The Search for Alexander the Great is a documentary,
history, tv movie film directed by Peter Sykes.
Friends, contemporaries and even enemies of Alexander the Great
gather in a tent to tell his tale through their eyes.
Narrator, played by James Mason.
Olympias, played by Jane Lapotaire.
Darius of Persia, played by Robert Stephens.
Philip II, played by Julian Glover.
Alexander, played by Nicholas Clay.
Hephaistion, played by Ian Charleson.
The Burning (aka Carnage) is a 1981 Canadian-American slasher film directed by Tony Maylam, and
starring Brian Matthews, Leah Ayres, Brian Backer, Larry Joshua, and Lou David.
Its plot follows a summer camp caretaker who is horribly burnt from a prank gone
wrong, where he seeks vengeance at a nearby summer camp years later.
The film marks the debuts of actors Jason Alexander,
Fisher Stevens, and Holly Hunter.
The film is an international co-production between the United States and Canada.
Based on the New York urban legend of the Cropsey maniac, the screenplay was written by Bob Weinstein and
Peter Lawrence, from a story conceived by producer Harvey Weinstein, Tony Maylam, and Brad Grey.
Rick Wakeman, of the progressive rock band Yes, composed the score.
The Burning was theatrically released on May 8, 1981, by Filmways.
Its critical reception was largely unfavorable, with many film critics deriding its
similarities to Friday the 13th and Friday the 13th Part 2 and its graphic violence.
However, it has since become a cult classic and received
positive reappraisal from film critics.
The film explores themes of aristotle, alexander the great,
ancient greece, 4th century bc, documentary.